Emad Mohamed

Team Lead

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/emad-mohamed-software-engineer/

Email: eng.emadmohamedphp@gmail.com

Phone: (+02) 01223872695

Website: https://emadmohdev.github.io/emad-mohamed-cv/

GitHub: https://github.com/EmadMohDev

Skype: emad.mohamed_edigits

Address: Giza -Egypt

Military status: Finished

Software Engineer with more than 12 years of experience in all phases of the software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design, and software testing mainly in PHP, MySql, Laravel, React,

, Design Patterns, Solid Principles, Git, HTML5 , CSS3 , JavaScript , Typescript , Bootstrap , Gulp Js , Material Ui , Tailwind CSS $\,$

I want to work in an environment that provides opportunities for professional development and enables me to learn more about dealing with difficult and critical situations.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science: Faculty of Engineering in Shoubra (2004 – 2009)

• Grade: Very Good

WORK HISTORY

ETAX

JULY 2023 until Now

Development Team Lead

• Lead the development team.

- Review the code to ensure it matches best practices.
- Send regular comments and feedback to every developer on the team.
- Share knowledge among team members.
- Encourage team members to use and experiment with the latest technologies.
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Review user stories and explain them to the team to ensure proper implementation.
- Perform smoke testing on finished features, ensuring projects are delivered on time and meet high standards.
- Deploy the project (both back-end and front-end) and configure the necessary settings on the Linux server.

Skills: Laravel – MySQL- Sql Server - PHP - Object Oriented Programming (OOP) - SOLID Design Principles - React - Javascript - TypeScript - Material UI - Tailwind CSS - Git - TFS - Linux

IVAS

Jan 2018 to June 2023

Team Lead

- Lead the Development team.
- Review the code to make sure that matching best practices, and name conventions.
- Support team in complicated tasks
- Make deep and full testing for all new projects
- Handle recruitment
- Good background in Linux development and administration.
- Sending regular updates about project status
- Building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Monitor a team consisting of 5 members (2 backend, 2 frontend, 1 UI/UX)
- Have a strong technical background and experience in leading a team of developers
- Responsible for managing the team's progress
- Ensuring that projects are delivered on time and to a high standard
- Providing technical guidance and support to all team members.
- Prioritize and manage workload.
- Ability to identify and translate business needs into technical requirements for successful project delivery.

Skills: Laravel – MySQL-PHP - Object Oriented Programming (OOP) - SOLID Design Principles - Software Design Patterns - Docker - Microservices - JavaScript - RabbitMQ - GraphQL – Redis - Debugging with PHP - Vue Js - React. js – GIT - REST APIs

IVAS Jan 2016 to Dec 2017

Senior Software Engineer

- Participates in all phases of the software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design, and software testing.
- work on "VAS" value-added service for web apps and mobile apps like call tones "rbts" and web push contents.
- Designs and develops relational database systems and their web interfaces.
- Provide written status reports & documentation for end users.
- Drawing up test strategies, stories, and test cases to test applications.
- Resolve technical issues through debugging, research, and investigation.
- Troubleshoot, test, and maintain the core product software and databases to ensure strong optimization and functionality.
- Follow industry best practices.
- Develop and deploy new features to facilitate related procedures and tools if necessary.
- Ensure the quality of the developed applications.
- Write clean, well designed code.
- Developing applications using laravel framework.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – Laravel- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) - JavaScript - Bootstrap – CSS3 – HTML5 - SASS - jQuery - Google Maps –GIT- REST APIs

SadaCode Jan 2015 to Dec 2015

Senior PHP Developer

• Developing web applications using the CakePHP framework.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – CakePHP – GIT- REST APIs – HTML – CSS –Java script - bootstrap

Edigits

Jan 2014 to Dec 2014

Senior PHP Developer

• Developing web applications using Laravel framework and WordPress CMS.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – Laravel- WordPress – GIT- REST APIs – HTML – CSS –Javascript - bootstrap

UKprosolutions Jan 2013 to Dec 2013

PHP Web Developer

• Developing web applications using the YII framework.

Skills: PHP - MySQL - YII--HTML- CSS - Javascript - GIT- REST APIs - bootstrap

SKILLS

• Experience With:

PHP - MySQL - Laravel - OOP - Design patterns - Solid Principles - MVC
RESTful & SOAP Apis - GIT - Graph QL - Docker - Redis - Google Maps - React- HTML - HTML5 - CSS - CSS3 - JavaScript - ESC6 - Bootstrap - jQuery - jQuery Ui - AJAX - JSON - YII framework - Cakephp framework - Codeignitor framework

LAI	N(;	·UA	GЕ

Arabic English

Naive

Very Good

PROJECTS

Tax Online Payment

- -The user can pay the taxes due on the unit by searching with the unit account code.
- After completing the payment process, an email is sent to the user with all the details related to the payment and the unit.
- In the system, the registered user can print the payment invoice for a specific unit.

✓Technologies: PHP - Laravel - React

Daftar 32:

- -in this system, the tax officer enters decisions and records various properties with all the required data, such as the property ledger details, previous property assessments, property description, property valuation, and property buildings.
- The officer also enters all the units within the property.
- -The officer enters the unit valuations.
- The officer links the unit to the garage.

✓Technologies: PHP - Laravel - React

Aghezty

https://aghezty.com

Ecommerce website where user can register and log in by his account Then make an order by 3 available types (cash / Visa NBE / Visa CIB) and It contains a wonderful filter through which you can search by price range, brand filter, category filter and there is a dashboard to completely control all items on the website

✓ Technologies: PHP - Laravel - bootstrap - SASS - Checkout js integration for CIB and NBE banks

Greetings

https://greeting.digizone.com.kw/v1

Entertainment web app that enables users to:

- 1- Cut the video
- 2- Cut the audio
- 3- Merge an image and audio to generate a video
- 4- Merge multiple images to generate a vide
- 5- Make animation on the generated video
- 6- Write on the image
- 7- Write on the video
- 8- Make water mark on the video

✓Technologies: PHP - Laravel – bootstrap - Vue Js - FFMPEG